Amit Hasan Sadhin

Present Address: Skudai, Johor Bahru, Johor, Malaysia

Phone No.: +601162325010
Email: samithasan7866@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amit-hasan-sadhin-9b5b64179/

Research Interests

Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence, Bio-medical Deep Learning, Neural Network, NLP. Object-detection.

CURRENT POSITION

↓ Vision Department as a research student for Gate Detection for drone racing.

Founding President and Programming Head for drone research and development

Johor, Malaysia, UTM Drone Lab. (July 2022 - Present) Johor, Malaysia, UTM Drone Club. (February 2022 - Present)

EDUCATION

♣ Bachelor of Computer Science (Software Engineering)

CGPA: 3.81 out of 4.00

Thesis: Road Crack Detection from Drone Images using Deep Learning

Models

Advisor: Siti Zaiton Bt. Mohd Hashim (Professor) and Dr. Hussein Ali Bin

Samma (Researcher)

Key Modules: Programing Languages (Java, C, C++), R programming, Probability & Statistical Data Analysis, Artificial Intelligence, Computational Intelligence, Statistics for data science, Software Engineering, Database, Computer Architecture, System Analysis and Design, Digital logic, Web programing, etc.

♣ Higher Secondary School Certification

GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

Courses: Physics 1&2, Chemistry, General Math, Higher Mathematics, ICT (Preliminary Programming), Biology, etc.

♣ Secondary School Certification

GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

Courses: Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Biology, etc.

University Of Technology Malaysia

Johor, Malaysia (October 2019 – Present)

Adamjee Cantonment College

Dhaka, Bangladesh (June 2016 – February 2018)

National Bangla High School

Dhaka, Bangladesh (January 2014 – December 2015)

PUBLICATIONS

Publication:

- 1. Amit Hasan Sadhin, "Real-time Tomato leaf disease Classification Using Convolutional Neural Network", Acta Informatica Malaysia, Jan. 2023
- Amit Hasan Sadhin, Nor Azman Bin Ismail, Syed Hamid Hussain Madni, Javed Ali, Gul Sahar, "User-Centred Design and Usability Evaluation of Smart home Energy Management System" International Research Journal of Modernization in Engineering Technology and Science, Aug. 2021
- **3. Amit Hasan Sadhin,** Reshad Rayhan, Safayet Hossain Tanmoy "A review of Convolutional Neural Network in emerging trends and opportunities in precision agriculture" Acta Informatica Malaysia, Feb. 2023

Journal Under Review:

1. Abdullah Bark Mohammed Bin Bsehr, El Moatasem Balla Ossama Mohamed Wahba, **Amit Hasan Sadhin**, Reshad Rayhan, Muhamad Aiman Fikri Bin Mohd Fadzli, "*Smartphone Controllable Spraying Pesticide Robot for agricultural fields*" Arabian journal for science and engineering.

Current Projects:

1. Amit Hasan Sadhin, Hussain Ali Bin Samma, Reshad Rayhan "A competitive analysis on modern object detection algorithms for underwater plastic objects".

SELECTED PROJECTS

Diabetes Prediction using Machine Learning

01/2020-02/2020: This is a simple project where I build a diabetes prediction system using a Machine learning concept. I personally work on this project t to learn Machine learning.

♣ House Price Prediction Using Machine Learning

03/2020-04/2020: To improve my understanding on Machine learning I work on this project using Boston dataset.

♣ Fake News Prediction using Machine Learning

05/2020-06/2020: This is a very simple project which I started to improve my knowledge on machine learning. The dataset is being collected from Kaggle.

4 Car Price Prediction Using Machine

07/2020-08/2020: This is a project which I started in the vacation just to learn how does the prediction system work on a dynamic environment.

4 Gold Price Prediction Using Machine Learning

09/2020-10/2020: This is a variation of the project Car Price Prediction Using Machine Learning.

Heart Disease Prediction using Machine

11/2020-12/2020: As per my learning improvement I worked on this project based on my personal interest with some dataset collected from various sources.

Credit Card Fraud Detection using Machine Learning

01/2021-02/2021: I started the project being inspired from an article published via CNN. Which highlighted the issues and the financial problem due to credit and debit card fraud.

♣ Customer Segmentation using K-Means Clustering with Python

03/2021-04/2021: The project I started as soon as I started understanding the K-Means in the beginning of 2021.

♣ Parkinson's disease Detection using Machine Learning

05/2021-06/2021: This is a simple project which detect whether a patient affected with Parkinson's or not via analysis the data.

♣ Spam mail prediction using Machine Learning

07/2021-08/2021: As now-a-days spam is become one of the most important concerns in mailing someone. This simple project follows the same concept that used by the current mail service provider.

♣ Movie Recommendation Using Machine Learning

10/2021-03/2022: Currently, I am working on a project which I call AI movie recommendation. For this project I am using few datasets which I found in Kaggle and other data provider websites.

♣ Breast Cancer Classification using Machine Learning

05/2022-11/2022: I am also working on a project just to fulfill my own interest in breast cancer classification as its became a burning issue for now. Although I am still learning via reading lots of research and their concept of classification. I hope in a very short time I will finish my work on this.

SELECTED EXPERIENCE

Position: R&D InternPlace: Dhaka, Bangladesh

Position: R &D Intern Place: Penang, Malaysia

Position: Core Member (Development)
Place: Johor, Malaysia

♣ Position: President and Head of Programming Place: UTM Bio-medical Lab, Johor, Malaysia Brac Bank Limited

(Aug 2020 – October 2020)

ViTrox Corporation Sdn. Bhd., (September 2022 – February 2023)

Google Developers Club., (January 2021 –March 2022)

UTM Drone Club

(September 2021- September 2022)

SKILLS

• Java, C++, Python, Java, Javascript, Opency, Data Analysis Tools: R, Excel, Tabular, Matlab, Jupyter Architecture

AREA OF EXPERTISE

• Python Programming, Machine Learning Model creation, Confident Learning, Classification, Database label error findings, CNN, YOLO family algorithms and Object detection.

SELECTED CERTIFICATIONS

- UTM Dean-list Awards (6th times)
- Varsity Hackathon-Best Business Idea Award for ML Software
- Google Developers Core Membership Award for 2021